of his adulterous affair is trying to
get
rid of the fire of god beloved how many
times
do we in our own walk with god
because the word of god the fire of god
brings conviction to us
we would rather get rid of the word of
god
there is a famine in the world for the
true
word how few there are who preach the
gospel
undiluted by human tradition
it is crucial that we share a gospel
that has not been watered down
whose strength has not been diminished
by human traditions
revelation 21 and verse 5 the bible says
and he that sat upon the throne said
behold i make
all things new and he said unto me right
for these words are true and
faithful i want to pause for a second
and encourage you with the idea that
god's words are
faithful amen if you
catch that amen if you understand and
agree
that the words of god that the word of
god
is faithful amen
amen amen i want you to notice again
titus 1 verse 9.
the bible says holding fast the faithful
word
as he has been taught that he may be
able to buy sound doctrine both to
exhort
and to convince the gangsters we are
seeing in these two verses
that the word of god is
faithful faithful i like depending upon
things that are
faithful because they will never let you
down but i want you to notice something
else about the word of god jeremiah 20
verse 9
the bible says here then i said i will
not make mention of him nor
speak anymore in his name but
his word was in my heart
as a burning fire shut up in my bones
and i was weary with forbearing and i
could not stay
the bible lets us know that god's word
is not only
faithful but it is also like a
fire in the bones god's word
is a fire amen amen this is why
one of my favorite verses in the bible
jeremiah 23 29 it says
is not my word like as a fire
save the lord and like a hammer that
breaketh the rock
in pieces listen to me
god's word is like a fire god's word
is faithful god's word is
trustworthy and we are to preach that
word
undiluted notice again with me hebrews
chapter 4 verse 12
for the word of god is quick and
powerful and
sharper than any two-edged sword
piercing
even to the dividing asunder of soul and
spirit and the joints and
and marrow and is a discerner of the
thoughts
and the intents of the heart this is
everything the word of god does and is
it is
faithful it is like a fire
and the word of god penetrates
our consciences the word of god is a
discerner
of thoughts it is quick and powerful and
sharper than any two-edged sword amen
amen
notice again with me proverbs 27 verse 6
faithful
are the wounds of a friend but the
kisses of an enemy
are are deceitful let me suggest to you
that the
the word of god is our friend
our faithful friend who yes even though
wounds us at times is wounding us
for our own good let me jump back for a
second
you see when the bible speaks
of the word being like a fire
i want you to understand or a light
this word here liked in john 3 19 is the
greek word
false and it means fire
so this is the condemnation that light
or
fire is coming to the world and men love
darkness rather than light or fire
because their deeds were evil
understand that fire is a source of
light
so the word of god is our faithful
friend
who has come into the world not to
condemn
but to save but i want you to understand
our response to the word of god
if we are living in darkness is that we
hate the light we hate the fire
we don't like the fire we don't like the
word
for everyone that doeth evil hated the
light
neither cometh to the light lest his
deeds
should be reproved
beloved i want you to understand the
word is like a faithful
friend the word is like a fire
that sheds light on us revealing
our inner thoughts if we love darkness
and do darkness we end up hating the
light we end up
hating the fire it brings conviction
upon us
not to condemn but to save us
follow this carefully we're gonna go to
the book of second samuel
chapter 11 beginning with verse 1.
the bible says here it came to pass
after the year
was expired at the time when kings go
forth to battle
that david sent joab and his servants
with him
and all israel and they destroyed the
children of ammon and besieged rabbah
but david
tarried still at jerusalem and it came
to pass
in an evening tide that david arose from
off his bed and walked upon the roof of
the king's house
and from the roof he saw a woman washing
herself
and the woman was very beautiful to look
upon and
david sent and inquired after the woman
and said is not this bathsheba the
daughter of elim the wife of uriah the
hittite
and david sent messengers and took her
and came in onto her
and lay with her for she was purified
from her uncleanness
and she returned to her house so david
ends up
sleeping with this man's wife and the
woman conceived and
sent and told david in saddam with child
and david sent to joab saying
send me uriah the hittite so uriah
is one of david's soldiers
and david said to uriah go down go down
to thy house and wash thy feet
and your ride departed out of the king's
house and there followed him a mess of
meat
from the king but urayo watch this uriah
slept at the door of the
king's house with all the servants of
his lord
and went not down to his own house now
uriah comes home from the battlefield
because david summons him
you get the idea right david
knows that bathsheba is pregnant so he
wants uriah
to go and be with his wife so that
he can cover his sin
yeah this is uriah's child i brought
your vial home and
your eye went but uriah does not do that
why did not thou go down to thine house
watch this answer guys and uriah said
unto david
the ark and israel and
judah abide in tents and my lord joab
and the servants of my lord are encamped
in the open fields shall i go into my
house
to eat and to drink and to lie with my
wife
as thou livest and as thy soul liveth
i will not do this thing
how can i go be with my wife when
the army is in battle
like david listen man i am your faithful
friend
i am your faithful friend david
my my focus
is on your mission is on god's
mission uriah is a
faithful friend to david
and when david had called him he did eat
and drink before him
and made him drunk and at evening he
went out to lie on his bed
with the servants of his lord but went
not down
to his house again
even in uriah's drunken state
he's like i'm not gonna go enjoy myself
while my brothers are out on the
battlefield
that's a faithful soldier man that's a
faithful friend david is
trying to ease his conscience and
every time he sees uriah his
conscience is convicting him
and when he finally realizes that uriah
will not be unfaithful to him
notice what he does set uriah in the
front of the hottest battle
and retire ye from him that he may be
smitten and die
you see there's something here i want
you to understand
david had to get rid of uriah
because of his affair with bathsheba
so now he's gonna whatever he needs to
do
to clear his conscience
he's gonna do that are you ready for
this
the name uriah it means
fire of god
uriah or urijah
david because of his adulterous affair
is
trying to get rid of the fire of god
beloved how many times
do we in our own walk with god
because the word of god the fire of god
brings conviction to us we would rather
get rid of the word of god let me say it
this way
it is easier to get rid of my enemy
than it is to deal with the enemy